FATEMA MALAM

UX Designer | Psychologist



+447796982124



malamfatema@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/fatema-malam



www.fmalam.com

Skills

User Centered Design
User Research
Data and Statistical Analysis
Information Architecture
Sketching
Wireframe and Prototype
Usability Testing
UI & Visual Design
Interpersonal skills
Communication skills
Organization Skills
Customer/client service

Tools/Programs

Sketch Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator Microsoft proficiency InVision Balsamiq HTML5/CSS3 JavaScript

Education

Certified UX Experience Design CareerFoundry | Germany | 2017 - 2018

MSc Psychiatric Research King College London | UK | 2013 - 2014

BSc Psychology City University London | UK | 2009 - 2012

About Me

A Psychologist-turned-UX Designer, bringing over 10 years of knowledge on human behavior to technology designs. Committed to discovering and solving complex problems (online & offline) and dedicated to creating intuitive, beautiful designs by understanding users' needs through emotional and cognitive empathy.

UX Design Projects

CareerFoundry | Germany | 2017 - 2018

UX Portfolio Website

 Designed and built a responsive portfolio website, coded from scratch with HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript

Ink Tank Tattoo App

- Designed a responsive Tattoo web app by developing and implementing solutions to users' problems through wireframes & prototypes, followed by usability testing & iteration
- Created the complete look and feel of the app by applying consistent typography, screen layout and UI kit

Flash Vocabulary App

 Designed early stage of Vocabulary learning app by running competitor and user research, followed by sketching wireframes, usability testing and refining prototypes for better user experience

Professional Experience

Social Media Executive

Vevian | London | 2016

- Expanded brand awareness by identifying creative engagement strategies and developing social media content to attract new customers
- Drove increase traffic to website and boosted sales by winning director/ fashion designer approval for an improved SEO strategy

Assistant Psychologist

NHS | London | 2014 - 2015

- Solved service users' problems by assessing their behavior & providing appropriate clinical diagnose and referrals
- Increased client base from 3 to 7 per day by managing work and time-frame, which successively resulted in more clients getting the help they needed

Clinical Researcher

NHS | London | 2013 - 2014

- Found and scheduled participants to take part in a psychosis study using incentive methods and time-frame
- Gained extensive information from interviewing participants with pre-existing psychotic disorder, followed by psychiatric questionnaires, observation of behavior and statistical analysis
- The study is now currently in the process of being published, due to great team effort, work ethic & trust